<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<!DOCTYPE article>
<article xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0">
  <info>
    <title></title>
  </info>
<section id="survey">
  <title>Survey</title>
  <section id="jan-hermann">
    <title>Jan Hermann</title>
    <para>
      In this project named Survey I led the team and also I was
      responsible for creating web interface of the application. Except
      that I made two Java classes for easier processing of the data.
      They are <emphasis>Response.java</emphasis> and
      <emphasis>XMLmanagement.java</emphasis>.
    </para>
    <section id="leading">
      <title>Leading</title>
      <para>
        As a leader I created the repository for the source code, web
        page about the project, parts of the documentation and I was
        trying to coordinate work on the project.
      </para>
      <para>
        For communication between members of the project, we were using
        web service Gitter. This we used for text messaging in a chat
        room about problems and ideas for the project.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section id="web-interface">
      <title>Web interface</title>
      <para>
        Web interface is used primarily for answering questions from
        users and storing responses from users. It was written in
        languages HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Java. For nicer output is
        used web framework Bootstrap.
      </para>
      <para>
        After the user run the web interface, Survey loads list of
        available questionnaires on the page. User selects one of them
        and form with questions is rendered. There the user will fill
        answers in given questionnaire. Once the user fills in answers
        and submits them, the application sends responses to the server.
        There they are processed through the JSP scriptlet. Then they
        are saved on the server in <emphasis>responses.xml</emphasis>
        file.
      </para>
      <para>
        Loading of the data is made via AJAX requests from the page to
        the server. For rendering is used HTML, CSS, JavaScript and
        Bootstrap. Every questionnaire with questions and answers is
        saved in <emphasis>survey.xml</emphasis> file. Processing of
        responses is handled on the server by Java and its JSP
        scriptlet.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section id="response.java">
      <title>Response.java</title>
      <para>
        This class creates XML document for storing responses. Questions
        and answers are stored in a hash map and then from it is made a
        XML document with response.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section id="xmlmanagement.java">
      <title>XMLmanagement.java</title>
      <para>
        This class is used for easier importing and exporting XML
        documents into files.
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>
</section>
</article>
